NICHOLAS SEIDL

Computer Vision - Software Engineer

I have experience in industry working on various **computer vision** and **machine learning** projects. I'm currently working at Apple on Intelligent System Experience - System Intelligence Machine Learning. I built a **live object detector (YOLO)** for Wayfair in Summer 2019. In Spring 2019, I worked on **failure analysis** of Apple's Neural Face Detector. In Spring + Summer 2018, I built two **web services** at Apple: one for **content analysis and retrieval** and one for **hosted image comparisons and history**.

Contact

nicholasseidl@gmail.com (650)-739-6674



<u>nseidl.io</u>



/in/nicholaskseidl



github.com/nseidl

Languages

Python, Java, Javascript, C, C++, Swift

Software

Tensorflow, TensorRT, Keras, TFLite, CoreML, EC2, Tornado, Flask, React, Typescript, Redux, Node, S3, Postgres, Elasticsearch, MySQL, REST, Docker

Courses

Algorithms and Data Structures Artificial Intelligence Linear Algebra Distributed Systems ML and Data Mining Object Oriented Design Computer Systems Programming Languages Probability and Statistics

Interests

Board Member of Pool Club, Photography Club, Basketball, Hiking

Experience

Apple Inc.
ISE SIML - Machine Learning Engineer

Cupertino, CA February 2020 - Present

•

Wayfair LLC

Boston, MA

Data Science - Computer Vision Engineer

June 2019 - Aug. 2019

- Implemented YOLO(v3) neural network for <u>live on-device object detection</u>
- Optimized with quantization, CUDA, cuDNN, TensorRT, and Tensor Cores
- Achieved 80x speedup in inference time and up to 4x smaller model sizes

Apple Inc.

Cupertino, CA

CVML - Machine Learning Engineer

Jan. 2019 - June 2019

- Analyzed failures of face detector to target aggressors and guide development
- Designed and automated failure analysis pipeline: inference → detection evaluation → failure analysis → visualization
- Curated datasets for different uses with custom model in the loop processes
- Managed data collection, selection, and annotation (guidelines, spec, and quality)

Apple Inc.

IMG QE - Full Stack Software Engineer

Cupertino, CA

Jan. 2018 - Aug. 2018

- Content Collection: audio/image/video/stream analysis and retrieval
- Integrated blob (Amazon S3) and metadata (Postgres) stores to serve content
- Leveraged Python and Tornado for asynchronous and non-blocking REST API
- Extracted attributes from audio, image, video, and stream content (Swift)
- Image Comparisons: image comparison web service with history
 - Rewrote backend in Flask; expanded API for frontend and hosted comparisons
 - Modularized backend so different comparison algorithms can easily be added

UnitedHealth Group - Optum Technology

Boston, MA

Boston, MA

GPA: 3.6 / 4.0

TDP - Backend Software Engineer

June 2017 - Aug. 2017

- Engineered pluggable Blockchain platform; adapted to bank transaction reconciliation and facilitation (big data)
- Designed, implemented, optimized backend and middle-tier pipeline (Python, Bash): MySQL → .csv → JSON → Elasticsearch → Blockchain → Hash Enforcer

Education

Northeastern University

Sep. 2015 - Dec. 2019

Khoury College of Computer Sciences

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science